The world of Shinigami
Shinigami literally means a "God of Death".
What?! A pair of sleeping skulls?!
なに？
ねんね
横髑髏二つ？
What?! A pair of sleeping skulls?!
ケケ、オレの勝ちだ、悪く思うなよ
Don't hate me for this, but I win again!
Hey, Ryuk! Wanna join us?
おいリューク、お前もやらないか
Come hang out with us for a change.
たまには仲間に入れよ
No... I'll pass...
いや、オレはいい…
Listen and follow voice of God…
Listen for the voice of God and never guess you will...
I haven't done anything but he said that he wanted to split up with me.
それであたし何にもしてないのに、急にキレできてよ
So what happened, what happened?
へぇ、それでそれで？
Yagami-kun, is there anything wrong?
夜神くん　どうしました？
Can you translate the previous sentences into Japanese please?
今の文章の和訳をお願いします
ふう…
Follow the voice of God and he shall calm the waves, and protect us from storms.
神の訓えに従うべし
さすれば、海の恵みは豊かになり
嵐はやって来ないだろう
At around 11 o'clock today,
本日、午前十一時頃
in the city of Yokohama, Kanagawa prefecture, a thirty year old man was found covered in blood at his apartment.
神奈川縣横浜市のアパートで、
30前後と見られ男性が、
血まみれで死亡しているところとが見つかれ
神奈川県警は、殺人事件として捜査します…
The Kanagawa police are currently treating this case as a suspected homicide.
次のニュースです
Next on the news...
Today in the district of Shibuya, Tokyo, a 25 year old woman was gagged and killed by her live-in partner.
本日正午過ぎ、東京都渋谷區で
同居している25歳の女性に暴行を加え殺害したとして
Today in the district of Shibuya, Tokyo, a 25 year old woman was gagged and killed by her live-in partner.
35 year old, Tofuji Naoki, is being held in custody charged with her murder.
35歳の男、兔富士直樹容疑者が
殺人の疑いで逮捕されました
Day after day...
毎日毎日…
It's always the same news.
同じことの繰り返し…
Completely... pointless...
まったく…くだらねぇ
This world is... rotting.
この世は…
腐ってる…
Rebirth
Another is the extinction of many species of life on the planet.
You seriously went to see that shit?!
マジで？あんなの見に行ったの…
It was a complete waste of time.
Species are becoming extinct at a faster rate than has occurred...
すげぇ時間の無駄だ、もっと金返せっと感じ…
You get the feeling that they're just trying to make money.
Death Note?
DEATH NOTE…
Literally translated as "a notebook of death".
直訳で「死のノート」…
ふん…
"How to use"...
使い方：
"The human whose name is written in this note shall die"?
このノートに名前を書かれた人間は…
死ぬ!?
ふん…
What a joke...
くだらない
Pretty sick though, it's no different to chain letters.
まったく…病んでるな
不幸の手紙から、全然進歩しちゃいない
"The human whose name is written in this note shall die"?
何が「名前を書かれた人間は死ぬ」だ
Seriously... I must be going insane...
まったく、どうかしてるな、僕も…
"This note will not take effect unless the writer has the person's face in their mind when they write his/her name."
書く人物の顔が頭に入っていないと効果はない
"Therefore, people sharing the same name will not be affected."
故に、同姓同名の人物に、一遍に効果は得られない
"If the cause of death is written within 40 seconds of writing the person's name, it will happen as it is written".
名前のあとに人間界単位で、40秒以内に死因を書くと
その通りになる
"If the cause of death is not specified, by default, the person will die of a heart attack".
書かなければ、死因は全て「心臓麻痺」になる
"Should a cause of death be specified, a further 6 minutes and 40 seconds are granted to write any further details".
死因を書くとさらに6分40秒
詳しい死の状況を記載する時間が与えられる
ふん、楽に死なせたり
So this means you can either kill them quickly or painfully, huh?
苦しませて死なせたりできるって事か
Quite a lot of detail to go into for a simple prank... Not bad.
悪戯もここまで手が込んでくると、
まぁまぁかな
Writing a name causes someone to die...?
名前を書くと死ぬ…か
Completely pointless.
本当にくだらない…
But wait...
待てよ…
On the off-chance that someone actually does die, wouldn't that make me a murderer?
万が一本当に死んだら、僕は殺人犯か？
ふん、まさかな…そんなわけあるはずない
Impossible. It'd never happen.
The phantom killer who attacked six people in Shinjuku's business district yesterday,
え…昨日、新宿の繁華街で六人ものを殺傷した通り魔は、
has now taken eight children and kindergarten teachers as hostages and is holed up in this nursery.
今なお、
幼児と保育士八人を人質に、この保育園にたてこもっております
警視庁は犯人を、音原田九郎、無職42歳と断定、
The police has identified the man as Otoharada Kurou, aged 42, unemployed.
It seems that they're about to begin negotiations...
説得を開始する模様です
Otoharada Kurou
According to the book, he should have a heart attack in 40 seconds.
40で心臓麻痺…
だったな
At the present time, we don't have a lot of information.
今のどころよくわかっておりません
You can't help but feel extremely concerned for the safety of the hostages.
人質の方の安危がなにより気になりますね
Indeed.
そうですね
That's all there is to report from the scene at this present moment.
以上、現場からお伝えしました
Thank you.
ありがとうございました
What do you make of the current situation, Hashimoto-san?
いかがでしょう橋本さん？
Well, all I can say is that we can only hope to resolve this situation quickly.
いや…一刻も早い解決を、望みますね
Nothing happened after all.
やっぱり何も起らない…
I guess that was to be expected.
まぁ、当たり前か
Ahh! Wait a minute! Something appears to be happening!
あっ、ちょっと待ってください
ん？
Ahh! Wait a minute! Something appears to be happening!
動きがあったようです
The hostages are coming out! They all appear to be unharmed!
人質が出てきました、
みんな無事のようです
The police are rushing the building as the hostages exit.
入れ替わるように、機動隊が突入
Has the culprit been apprehended?!
犯人逮捕でしょうか
あ…はい、
Yes.
We've just heard that the culprit was found dead in the nursery!
たった今、情報が入りました
犯人は保育園内で死亡！
Yes, it looks like the culprit is dead!!
犯人は死亡した模様です
Dead?!
死亡?!
Otoharada Kurou
The riot police have denied shooting the man.
機動隊は、「射殺したのではない」と強調しております
Then, this might imply that he committed suicide when he found himself cornered?
では、追い詰められての自殺ということでしょうか
According to the hostages' statements, "he suddenly collapsed".
それが…人質の証言では、犯人は突然倒れたと話しています
A heart attack...
心臓麻痺…
い…いや
No.
Coincidence... This has to be a coincidence.
偶然だ
偶然に決まってる
Light?
月
It's already 6:30. Don't you have cram school today?
もう六時半になるわよ
今日は塾の日でしょ？
I'm just getting ready.
ああ、今支度してること
Death Note.
デスノート…、でも万一これが本物だとしたら…
It's a long shot, but if this is the real thing...
もう一度試してみる価値はある
I need to test it again.
In which case the victim should probably be a criminal.
そうなると…やはり犯罪者か…
But if they're too infamous, there's the possibility that their deaths may initially be covered up...
しかしあまり大物でもまずい…
たとえ死んでも、その事実を暫く隠される可能性がある
I need to see results now!
すぐに結果が欲しい…
Yo, Yochi.
よう、良チン
W-What do you want Sudou?
な…何、素藤くん
Lend me 'bout 2,000 yen will ya?
二千円でいいから貸してよ
え、ま…またですか
...again?
Sudou...
素藤…
Are you saying you don't wanna?
なに、嫌の？
I could try killing him...
殺してみるか
No. Where possible I should avoid people I know.
いや、身近な人間はなるべく避けたほうがいいな…
Then again, I shouldn't be too bothered, nobody will care if one or two guys like him disappear.
いや、そんな気にすることもないか
どうせあんな奴の一人や二人、
死んでも誰も、何も思わない
I'll be going to the arcade again on my way home with this!
ヒュッー、これで帰りゲーセン行くぜ
Hey, Maki, you wanna come out for drinks with the University crowd at 10:00 tomorrow?
マキ、明日合コンやるんだけど来ない？
Yeah, definitely!
いくいく
Oh, me too!
え、あたしも
Damn it! That stupid old hag isn't here to pick me up!
なんだよ、うちのババァ、
迎えに来てねぇじゃねぇかよ！
Jeez.. Thinking about this really makes you realize just how many people the world would actually be better off without.
まったく…こうなるとどいつもこいつも、
殺したほうが、世の中の為になり奴ばかりに見えてくる
おねえさん
Hey baby!
Fancy having some fun with us?
今から俺らと遊ばない？
That's Takuo-san for you, you've certainly bagged another hottie!
さすがタクさん、すんげぇ美人ゲット
The name's Shibuimaru Takuo, but you can call me Shibutaku.
俺、渋井丸拓男、略してシブタク
へへへ、付き合ってよ～素敵なおねえさん
Hang out with us for a while, baby.
こ…困ります…
Please don't trouble me...
She doesn't want us to "trouble her"!
「困ります…」だって、カワイイ
How cute!
Guys, take them off for her.
ならめくって、脱がして全部
Can we?!
えっ、いいッスか？
Stop!
やめて…
Please!
お願い…やめて
Stop!!
All the different variations of writing the name "Shibuimaru Takuo".
Now, let's see what happens!
さあ…どうなる？
Wait!
待ってよ
Takuo! Look out!!
タク、危ねぇ！
T-That settles it...
決…決まりだ！
The Death Note.. It's the real deal!
デスノートは…本物だ!!
Takuo!
タク…
Dickhead!
馬…馬鹿野郎
Why'd he jump out like that?!
急に飛び出しやがっ…
I guess... I'd better get going soon.
さて…そろそろ行くか
It's been five days since then...
あれから五日…
I guess... I'd better get going soon.
さて、そろそろ行くか…
ん？お出かけかいリューク
Eh, you going out somewhere, Ryuk?
ここはどこ至って不毛だぜ
Wherever you go in our world, it'll only be desolate.
I dropped my Death Note.
デスノートを落としちまった…
Jeez, you really fucked up this time.
今度はまたすげぇドジしたなぁ
Hang on, didn't you cheat a second Death Note out of the Shinigami Overlord?
ジ　　ジ　　ィ
つぅか、おめぇ死神大王を騙くらかして二冊持てたじゃねぇか
Don't tell me you lost both of 'em?
二冊共落としたのかよ？
Do ya even know where ya dropped it?
で、どこに落としたか分ってるわけ？
The human world.
下　界
人間界…
Wha--?!
えっ？
Welcome home.
おかえり
You're pretty early today, Light.
早かったわね、月
Yeah...
ああ、ただいま、母さん
I'm back, mother...
Huh?
ああ、全国模試の結果ね
Oh, you want the results of the national mock exams, right?
Quickly!
はやく
Here you go.
はい
Wow! Number one again!
あら、また一位
You really tried hard, didn't you, Light?
頑張ったわね月
I guess. I'm going to study in my room, so don't interrupt.
まぁね
じゃあ勉強するから、邪魔しないでね
I guess. I'm going to study in my room, so don't interrupt.
Yes, yes.
はいはい
ああ、月
Oh yes, Light!
Do you want anything?
何が欲しい物はないの？
You can ask for whatever you like.
何でも言って
別にないよ、母さん
Nothing really, mother.
I already got what I want.
…欲しい物は手に入った
I see that you've taken quite a shine to it.
気に入ってるようだな
Why are you so surprised?
何故そんなに驚く？
I am Ryuk, the Shinigami who dropped that notebook.
そのノートの落とし主、死神のリュークだ
Judging by that face of yours earlier, it seems you've already realized that that is no ordinary notebook.
さっきの様子だと、
もうそれがただのノートじゃないって分ってるんだろ？
Judging by that face of yours earlier, it seems you've already realized that that is no ordinary notebook.
A Shinigami, huh?
死神か…
驚いてないよ、リューク
I'm not surprised, Ryuk...
In fact, I've been waiting for you, Ryuk.
いや…待ってたよ、リューク
Ohh?
ほう？
I've already realized that this Shinigami's notebook is real.
僕はすでに、死神のノートを、現実だと疑ってなかったが…
こうしていろんな事を直視することで、
And after seeing its results, I can act with certainty.
ますます確信を持って行動できる
I see. You surprise me.
なるほどな
お前には驚かされるぜ
I see. You surprise me.
In the past, I've heard of instances where a Death Note has appeared in the human world,
過去にデスノートが人間界に出回った話は、
俺も何度か聞いた事があったが…
but you're the first person to have written this many names in just five days.
たった五天でここまでやったのはお前が初めてだ
Normally, people are too frightened to write as much as this.
並じゃビビってここまで書けない
覚悟はできてるよリューク
I've already prepared myself, Ryuk.
I knowingly used a Shinigami's notebook, and now a Shinigami has come.
僕は死神のノートを分っていて使った
そして死神が来た…
僕はどうなる？
What'll happen to me? Are you going to take my soul?
魂を取られるのか？
Huh? What are you talking about?
あん？なんだそれ
Is this some kind of fantasy created by humans?
人間がつくった勝手なイメージか？
I'm not going to do anything to you.
俺はお前に何にもしない
えっ？
The moment that notebook fell to this world, it became the property of the human world.
人間界の地に着いた時点で、
ノートは人間界のものになる
In other words, that notebook belongs to you.
つまりそいつはもう、お前のものだ
M-Mine?
僕の…もの…
If you don't want it, you can pass it to someone else.
いらなきゃ他の人間に回せ
その時はお前のデスノートに関する記憶だけ消させてもらう
But I reserve the right to erase your memory of the Death Note if you do.
So you're telling me that there's really no trade-off for using the Death Note?
じゃあ、本当にデスノートを使った代償って…
何もないんだな？
Since you insist on knowing, there is the fear and suffering that is faced only by those humans who use Death Notes.
強いて言えば、
そのノートを使った人間にしか訪れない苦悩や恐怖…
And finally, when you die, it falls to me to write your name in my Death Note.
そしてお前が死んだ時、
オレがお前の名前を、オレのノートに書くことになるが…
And finally, when you die, it falls to me to write your name in my Death Note.
Don't assume that a human who's used the Death Note can go to Heaven or Hell.
デスノートを使った人間が…
天国や地獄にいけると思うな
That's all.
それだけだ
You'll have something to look forward to when you die.
死んでからのお楽しみだ
月？
Light?
It's okay. Answer it.
大丈夫だ、出てみろ
What?
なに？
リンゴ持ってきたわよ
I've brought you some apples. The neighbours brought them round to share.
すそわ
お隣さんからお裾分け
I've brought you some apples. The neighbours brought them round to share.
なぁにこんな暗くして…
Why is it so dark in there?
You'll ruin your eyesight you know.
目を悪くするわよ
What's going on? Can't mother see him?
どういうことだ？
まったくもう…
_
What's going on? Can't mother see him?
母さんには見えていないのか
That used to be my notebook, so as the current user you're the only one who can see me, and of course the only one who can hear me.
そのノートは元々、俺が持っていた物だ
それを使うことになったお前だけが、
オレの姿を見えることができる
That used to be my notebook, so as the current user you're the only one who can see me, and of course the only one who can hear me.
勿論声も、
お前にしか聞こえない
言わばデスノートは、人間ライトと死神リュークを繋ぐ絆だ
That Death Note is the bond that ties you, the human, to me, Ryuk, the Shinigami, so to speak.
Mmm, nice!
…美味い
Can I ask you one more thing.. Why me?
じゃあもうひとつ聞くけど…
何故僕を選んだ？
Can I ask you one more thing.. Why me?
Are you listening?
おい、聞いてるのか
Wow, apples in the human world are damn good.
すごいぜ人間界のリンゴは
They're.. how to say it..
語彙のなんてんだ？
"juicy"?
Juicy？
(Juicy=ジューシー)
Answer the question.
質問に答えろよ
ふん、選んじゃいない
I didn't pick you.
オレはただノートを落としただけだ
I just happened to drop the notebook.
What, did you think you'd been picked because you're smart or something?
賢い自分が選ばれたでも思ったのか？
Don't be so vain.
うぬぼれるな
It just happened to fall around here, and you just happened to pick it up.
偶々この当たりに落ち、
偶々お前が拾った
それだけのことだ
That's why I wrote it in the most popular human language, English.
だから人間界で一番ポピュラーな英語で説明をつけたんだぜ
So why did you drop it?!
じゃあ何故落とした！
You went through the whole trouble of writing down instructions, so don't tell me you just happened to drop it by accident!
丁寧に使い方まで書いて…
間違って落としたなんて言うなよ
Why you say... because I was bored.
何故かっで…
退屈だったから
Why you say... because I was bored.
退屈…
Bored?!
The truth is that most Shinigami haven't got much to do.
実際今の死神ってのは暇でね
They mainly sleep or gamble.
昼寝してるか、
博打うってるかだ
Try writing any names in your book, and they'll laugh at you for trying too hard.
下手にデスノートに名前なんて書いてると、
「何頑張っちゃってるの？」って笑われる
Even if you write the name of someone living in the Shinigami world, they won't die, and it's no fun killing humans from the Shinigami world.
死神界のやつをノートに書いても死なない、
かっといて自分は死神界にいるのに、
人間界の奴を殺しても面白くも何ともない
So I figured it'd be more fun in this world.
こっちに来る方が面白いとオレは踏んだ
Anyway, you seem to have written quite a few names here.
それにしても、随分名前書いたな
But why did you only write the cause of death for the guy that was run over by a dump truck?
しかし、何でダンプにはねられた奴しか死因を書いてないんだ？
If you don't write the cause of death, the victim dies of a heart attack.
死因を書かなければ皆、心臓麻痺で死ぬ
That's the best thing about the Death Note, Ryuk.
そこがデスノートの一番いいどころだよ、リューク
はぁ？
I've already begun to exhaust the list of high profile criminals, and I'm gradually including people that commit less serious crimes.
既に主だった犯罪者の名前は書き尽くし、
徐徐に悪人のレベルを下げてる
And what does that achieve?
それが何だっというんだ？
どんなお馬鹿でも、
悪人が誰かに消されているって事に気づくだろ？
No matter how stupid people are, they'll eventually realize that someone is wiping out these criminals.
I'm going to let the world know of my existence.
世の中に知らしめるんだ…
僕の存在を…
That there is someone who can, and will, pass righteous judgement!
正義の裁きを下す者がいるって事を！
いや、しかし…
But what do you plan to achieve by passing this "righteous judgement"?
正義の裁きを下してどうするつもりだ？
Why bother?
何故そんな事を？
Because... I'm also bored.
僕も…退屈だったから
Of course, at first I didn't believe it, but that notebook has a kind of magic that compels humans to try it at least once.
もちろん最初は信じなかった、
でもそのノートには…
人間なら誰でも一度は試してみたくなる魔力がある
I k-killed them...
こ…殺してしまった…
二人も…
Two of them...
この…僕が…
命なのに…軽いはずがない
It's a life. The consequences can't be light.
Do I have the right to pass judgements on others?
僕に勝手に、人を裁く権利があるのか？
But wait, it's not like that. This is what I've always thought.
いや…
違う！
But wait, it's not like that. This is what I've always thought.
いつも思ってた事じゃないか？
This world is rotting.
世の中腐っている…
Those who are rotting deserve to die.
腐ってる奴は死んだほうがいい！
Someone...
誰かが…誰かがやらなくてはいけないんだ
Someone has to do it!
自らの精神や命を犠牲にしてでも…
Sacrificing their own life and soul, because the world just can't continue like this!
このままじゃ…いけないんだ
If someone else had picked up this notebook, would they be able to erase all the unnecessary people from this world?
もし他の誰かが、このノートを拾ったとして…
この世に不必要な人間を消すことの出来る奴がいるか
No way!
いるわけがない
でも僕なら…
But I can... I can do it!
僕にならできる！
In fact, I'm the only one who can do it!
いや…
僕にしかできないんだ
I'll do it. I'll use the Death Note..
やろう…デスノートで…
To change the world!
世の中を変えてやる！
I began to think of it as "tidying up the world", and continued to write down the names of the most monstrous criminals.
まずは地球の掃除と思って、
凶悪犯の名前を書き続けた
やがて、誰も悪い事ができなくなるように…
Eventually no one will be able to commit a crime.
Then, behind the fact that deserving criminals are dying of heart attacks,
そして、罪を受けて当然な悪人が心臓麻痺で死んでいく裏で、
I'll gradually start killing of those who cause problems for innocent people, through illness and accidental death.
道徳のない人間、人に迷惑をかける人間を…
病死や事故死で少しずつ消していく…
This way it's certain that the world will become a better place.
そうすれば、
確実に世界はいい方向に進んでいく
Then, I'll have created a world filled with those I've judged to be kind and hard working.
そして、僕が認めた、
真面目で心の優しい人間だけの世界を作り上げていく
If you do that, you'll be the only fucked up person left.
そんなことしたら、性格悪いのはお前だけになるぞ
What do you mean, Ryuk?
何を言ってるんだ、リューク
I'm probably the most virtuous student in the country.
僕は日本一と言ってもいいくらいの、
真面目な優等生だよ
And then...
そして僕も…
I'll become the God of my new world!
新世界の神となる！
I knew it! Humans are... so much fun!
やっぱり人間って…
面白…
To be continued
僕に逆らうとどうなるか…
世界中が注目しているよ
L …